rtcamp.com 2019-08-07

# Privacy Policy

This page specifies the data that we collect, how we collect it and why we collect it. If you have any additional queries, or if we have failed to provide you with any information, you can contact us via our [Contact Page](https://rtcamp.com/contact/) and we will get back to you within two working days.

The overarching principles of our policy are as follows:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we have to
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone outside of rtCamp unless explicitly specified in this document
  * We don’t store any of your personal information unless we need it for testing, development or to make our services better. Even in this case, we make sure to irreversibly delete it as soon as it has served its purpose

This has been our policy before GDPR, and will be our policy going forward, regardless of regulation.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact forms

You may voluntarily provide us with your name and email address to set up a contact request or subscribe to our newsletter.

We use Mailchimp to send and manage our newsletter subscriptions. When you voluntarily subscribe to our newsletter, we send your name and email to Mailchimp.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). We also use social share buttons for Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google on our site and in our newsletters. Embedded content these or any embedded websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We track visitors and their movement across this site. Tracking includes IP addresses, type of browser and referrer. Such information is not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

We use Google Analytics which allows us to collect information about how you use our site. If you access our website directly (and not via an email) your visits will be tracked anonymously. We use Google Analytics and Hotjar to understand how our website is being used in order to improve the experience for you. All user data is anonymous.

For our [careers site](https://careers.rtcamp.com/), we use referral tracking. This is strictly opt-in. As part of this, we collect

  * Landing Page Referring URL 
  * IP address of referrer 
  * Date of referral 

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

### What rights you have over your data

As per the GDPR, you can request us for an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

Though unlikely, we reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy without providing you with advance notice.

If you have any additional queries, or if we have failed to provide you with any information, you can contact us via our [Contact Page](https://rtcamp.com/contact/) and we will get back to you within two working days.
